Jacob Sansom

Email: jhsansom@umich.edu Website: jhsansom.github.io LinkedIn: jhsansom

ABOUT ME

I am a Ph.D. student at the University of Michigan. I am developing AI systems that emulate and model the unique manner in which humans learn. Namely, I aim to computationally model the reasoning processes and memory systems that enable humans to learn from direct instruction and small amounts of experience.

EDUCATION

The University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI
Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering	2024–Current
Advisors: Honglak Lee and Joyce Chai	
The University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI
M.S. in Computer Science and Engineering	2022-2024
The University of Texas at Austin	Austin, TX
B.S. in Computational Engineering, Certificate in Evidence and Inquiry	2016-2020

FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS

• National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship	Winter 2024
CSE Department Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor Award	Fall 2023
CSE Department Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor Award	Winter 2023
• Northrop Grumman BRAVO to our Stars (3x)	2021 - 2022
• FSTI Award for Excellence in Chemistry	Spring 2018
• TIDES Advanced Summer Research Fellowship	Summer 2017
• Engineering Honors Scholarship	2016-2020
• Polymathic Scholars Interdisciplinary Humanities and Natural Science Honors	2016-2020

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] A. Liu, X. Wang, **J. Sansom**, Y. Fu, J. Kim, S. Sohn, and H. Lee, "Interactive and Expressive Code-Augmented Planning with Large Language Models", in *Submission*.
- [2] Y. Huang, **J. Sansom**, Z. Ma, F. Gervits, and J. Chai, "DriVLMe: Exploring Foundation Models as Autonomous Driving Agents That Perceive, Communicate, and Navigate", in *IROS*, 2024.
- [3] Z. Ma, **J. Sansom**, R. Peng, and J. Chai, "Towards A Holistic Landscape of Situated Theory of Mind in Large Language Models", in *Findings of EMNLP*, 2023.
- [4] E. Lejeune, A. Khang, **J. Sansom**, and M. Sacks, "FM-Track: A Fiducial Marker Tracking Software for Studying Cell Mechanics in a Three-Dimensional Environment", in *SoftwareX 11*, 2020, p. 100417.
- [5] A. Khang, A. Rodriguez, M. Schroeder, **J. Sansom**, E. Lejeune, and M. Sacks, "Quantifying Heart Valve Interstitial Cell Contractile State Using Highly Tunable Poly(Ethylene Glycol) Hydrogels", in *Acta Biomaterialia* 96, 2019, pp. 354–367.

Industry Experience

LG AI Research
Research Intern
Ann Arbor, MI
2023–2024

- Crowdsourced more than 10,000 examples of people using the internet for AI model training
 - * Created a Chromium extension for recording browser interactions and a server for hosting virtual machines
 - * Automated task creation and quality checks of crowdsourced data

Northrop Grumman

San Diego, CA

Systems Engineer (Technical Level II), Pathways Rotational Training Program

2020 - 2022

- Leveraged my expertise in the HW-, SW-, and algorithm-level architecture of a fielded, software-defined radio to:
 - * Assist a cross-organizational team with the design and deployment of a novel DSP algorithm
 - * Author and obtain customer funding for a proposal detailing improvements to a fielded DSP algorithm
- Created the AI Corporate Catalog, a company-wide database of AI/ML capabilities
- Led a small team in the design and deployment of a C++ unit testing infrastructure

Ansys Government Initiatives (formerly Analytical Graphics Inc.)

Exton, PA

Corporate Systems Engineering Intern

Summer 2019

- Used Python to quantify the accuracy of orbital decay forecasts in STK, AGI's primary software offering
- Helped develop multiple simulations that modeled orbital dynamics, communications links, and terrain effects
- Outlined a strategy to bolster STK's collaborative capabilities and presented it to the senior development team

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• Graduate Student Instructor at the University of Michigan (Outstanding GSI Award)

Introduction to Natural Language Processing (EECS 487)

Winter 2023

• Graduate Student Instructor at the University of Michigan (Outstanding GSI Award)
Introduction to Natural Language Processing (EECS 487)

Fall 2023

Presentations

• J. Sansom "Investigating Methodology for Global Optimization," presented at the College of Natural Sciences Undergraduate Research Forum. April 13th, 2018; Austin, TX. (FSTI Award for Excellence in Chemistry)

SKILLS

- Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB, Bash
- Software Tools: PyTorch, Jax, NLTK, Transformers, W&B, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, SciPy, Git, Docker, OpenMP, Selenium, Playwright, Flask

Extracurricular Activities

• Chair of Northrop Grumman Pathways Professional Development Committee 2021–2022

Planned and successfully launched a new technical mentorship program for early-career engineers

• Volunteer at the Arc and the Rosedale School 2018–2019 Helped adults and children with cognitive disabilities develop life skills and provided constant positive feedback

• Undergraduate Representative for the Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics 2018–2019

Worked with leaders to offer membership and resources to the new undergraduate computational sciences program

• Eagle Scout and Troop Guide in the Boy Scouts of America

Led a team of 30 to construct shelves for a homeless shelter. Taught younger scouts various scouting skills

2016